(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
1st Generation Princess Party ♪♪
#ホロ1期生6周年
#Holo1stGen6thAnniversary
お姫様にしてよ！
作詞：指原莉乃 作曲：Gou Ishikuro / Yu-ki Kokubo
Make me a Princess!
Lyrics: Rino Sashihara / Composition: Gou Ishikuro & Yu-ki Kokubo
ずっと将来の夢は 王子の横のキラキラgirlに
My dream for the future has always been to be the sparkling girl by the prince's side.
ドレスを着て 舞踏会
Wearing a dress to the ball.
超可愛！
Super cute!
大人になれば勝手に なれるものだと思ってた
I thought I'd naturally become one when I grew up.
あれあれ？気付けば 武闘派のキュート社会人
Wait, wait? Before I knew it, I'm a militant cute working adult.
優雅なモーニングは この世界になくて
Elegant mornings don't exist in this world,
スヌーズは騒がしい
And the snooze button is so noisy.
でもでも 魔法使いは見ているもん
But, but, the wizard is watching me.
お姫様にしてよ！ ほら白馬の王子様よ
Make me a princess! Look, there's my prince on a white horse.
駆け巡ろうよ
Let's ride around together!
毒リンゴかじって眠りにつくわ
I'll bite a poisoned apple and go to sleep.
ガラスの靴は片方だけ 履いたまま残してあげる
I'll leave behind a glass slipper, keeping the other one on.
全員ヒロイン降臨LOVE！
Everyone's a heroine, descending LOVE!
あいらびゅー！
I love you!
あいたーい！
I want to see you!
頑張ってる私 仮眠取りたいとこだけど
I'm working hard, and though I want to take a nap,
ランチはクリームのパスタ
Lunch is creamy pasta.
超可愛！
Super cute!
小鳥さんと歌って 突然くるくる回って
Singing with the birds and suddenly spinning around.
世界はいつでも 私の全て見守る
The world is always watching over all of me.
可愛い香水は職場に似合わないし
Cute perfume doesn't suit the workplace,
満員の電車には
And on these crowded trains...
私の世界は狭すぎる
My world is much too narrow.
お姫様になって ふわふわのベッドでごろなり
Becoming a princess and rolling around on a fluffy bed.
愛を語ろう
Let's talk about love.
深く眠ったら 優しいキスを
After I fall into a deep sleep, give me a gentle kiss.
ちょっと待ってよ仕事のこと 今ここで話さないでよ
Wait a minute, don't talk about work right now.
戦うヒロイン降臨LOVE！
Fighting heroines, descending LOVE!
あいらびゅー！
I love you!
あいたーい！
I want to see you!
誰が
Who...
好き？
do you like?
だー
Da-
りー
ri-
んー
n-
ぐー
gu-
だ！
da!
焼きたて できたて 魔法のランプどこ？
Freshly baked, freshly made, where's the magic lamp?
守ってもらってばかりは嫌だし
I don't want to just be protected all the time.
強くて甘いの
Strong and sweet.
令和のプリンセスよ
We're the princesses of the Reiwa era.
とはいえこのシーンは 君からグッときて
That said, in this scene, you should move closer.
近付いてさ 苦い時でしょ？
Come closer, it's a bitter time, right?
よーいスタート！
Ready, start!
お姫様にしてよ！
Make me a princess!
ほら白馬の王子様よ 駆け巡ろうよ
Look, there's my prince on a white horse. Let's ride around together!
毒リンゴかじって眠りについた
I bit the poisoned apple and fell asleep.
キスされてすぐ目を覚まして
I woke up right after being kissed,
区役所行って婚姻届
And headed to the ward office for the marriage registration.
全員ヒロイン降臨LOVE！
Everyone's a heroine, descending LOVE!
あいらびゅー！
I love you!
あいたーい！
I want to see you!
せーの！ イコラLOVE！
One, two! Ikora LOVE!
はい！ ということで始まりましたー！
Alright! And so it begins!
イエーイ！ 1期生ライブ！
Yay! 1st Gen Live!
ということで、最初は自己紹介していきましょう！
So, let's start with self-introductions!
はーい！ 皆さんこんこんきつね！ 白上フブキでーす！
Hi! Kon-kon kitsune, everyone! I'm Shirakami Fubuki!
そして！ ホロライブの清楚担当、みんなのアイドル夏色まつりでーす！
And! Hololive's purity representative and everyone's idol, Natsuiro Matsuri!
わっしょーい！
Wasshoi!
はい、みんなアローナ！ ホロライブの癒やし系ハーフエルフ、アキロゼこと秋・ローゼンタールです！
Hi, alona everyone! Hololive's healing half-elf, Aki Rosenthal, also known as Aki-Rose!
はーい！ はあちゃまっちゃまー！
Hi! Haachama-chama!
ワールドワイドの最強アイドル、はあちゃまこと赤井はあとでーす！
The worldwide strongest idol, Akai Haato, also known as Haachama!
はい！ ということで本日ハッシュタグこちらですね！
Alright! And here's today's hashtag!
ホロ1期生6周年でお願いしまーす！
Please use #Holo1stGen6thAnniversary!
6周年！おめでとう！
6th Anniversary! Congratulations!
ついに我々、6周年でございます。
Finally, we have reached our 6th anniversary.
すごいねー。
It's amazing.
今回、6周年記念ライブのコンセプトが、
The concept of this 6th anniversary commemorative live is,
みんなお姫様ということで、はい。
everyone as a princess, yes.
ちょっとね、1曲目「お姫様にしてよ！」から歌わせていただきました！
So, we started off by singing "Make Me a Princess!" as our first song!
ちょっと今回、なんとステージも、1期生のライブ仕様になりました！
This time, incredibly, the stage is also customized for the 1st Generation's live!
可愛い！すごい！
So cute! Amazing!
めちゃくちゃ豪華じゃない？
Isn't it incredibly luxurious?
我々の城、みんなで建てた城ですよ！
It's our castle, the castle we all built together!
みんなのおかげで、こんな立派な城が建ちました！ありがとうございます！
Thanks to everyone, such a magnificent castle has been built! Thank you so much!
そしてですね、上の方、実は時計があるんですが、
And, you see, up there, there's actually a clock,
この時計、12時と見せかけて、実は23時59分で止まってます！
but although it looks like 12 o'clock, it's actually stopped at 23:59!
1分前！
1 minute before!
魔法が解けないね！
The magic won't wear off!
魔法が解けないんです。そうなんです。
The magic doesn't wear off. That's right.
そしてなんと今回ステージ、今日来てくれている皆さんのステージ、
And incredibly, this time, the stage... for everyone who came today,
観客席がなんと三階席まである！
there are even spectator seats up to the third level!
やったー！すごい！
Yay! Amazing!
いや、すごい、すごい人ですよ、これはね。
Wow, there are so many people here.
おみんなのコールが聞こえる気がする。
I feel like I can hear everyone's cheers.
ということで、我々6周年を迎えましたので、改めてちょっと振り返ってとか、
So, since we've reached our 6th anniversary, let's look back on things again,
これから我々7年目に向けてでもいいんですけど、
or talk about our upcoming 7th year,
ライブの意気込みでもいいですし。
or our enthusiasm for the live.
毎年周年来てるけど、もうそんなに経ったかーって。
We have an anniversary every year, but I'm like, "Has it already been that long?"
そうだね、ほんとに。
That's true, really.
はあちゃまある？
Haachama, do you have something?
いや、長いですね、7年目もね、やっぱり。
It's been a long time. For the 7th year, too, as expected,
アイドルらしく、最強アイドルとして頑張っていきたいと思います！
I want to keep doing my best as the strongest idol!
ではアキちゃん！
Now, Aki-chan!
まさか、7年も続けてこられるっていうのは想像もしてなかったけど、
I never imagined that I'd be able to keep going for 7 years,
でも今こうやってね、みんなと一緒にライブできるのはめちゃくちゃ嬉しい！
but being able to perform a live with everyone like this now makes me so incredibly happy!
7年目もラッキーセブンにあやかっていっぱい頑張っていきたいと思います！
For the 7th year, I want to work hard and make the most of that "Lucky 7"!
今日はみんな王子様だからね。
Since everyone is a prince today.
まつりも7年目に向けて頑張るので、今年こそは王子様を見つけたいと思います！
I'm also going to do my best for our 7th year, so I hope to finally find my prince this year!
まつりすの中にいるかなー？
I wonder if he's among the Matsuris?
やめてください。
Please stop that.
そして、昨年頑張った我々は本当に...
And for the 6th year, we really worked hard last year...
7年目でラッキーセブンで、いいこといっぱいあるといいなと思っております。
I hope many good things happen in our 7th year, the "Lucky 7".
それもこれも、今日来てくれている王子様の皆さんのおかげなので。
And all of this is thanks to all the princes who came today.
王子様か、今日はおじ...
Are they princes, or today, are they "oji"...
おじさま！
Old men!
おじさま大歓迎！おじもいるのか。
Old men are very welcome! Are there "oji" too?
今日見てくれている王子様たちのために、我々歌うので...
Since we're going to sing for the princes watching today...
さて、じゃあ次の曲に行きましょうかね。
Well then, let's move on to the next song.
次は何だろう？え？なんかすごい音がした！
What's next? Eh? I heard a strange sound!
何、何？痛い、頭痛い！なんか白身から出てきそう！
What, what is it? It hurts, my head hurts! Something's coming out of the whites!
プリにゃんモードはピピピのピ
Prinyan Mode is Pipipi no Pi
はにゃ～～ん！
Hanyaan!
忘れちゃったのかにゃん？
Did you forget about me-nyan?
あたちが、ホワイトプリにゃんだにゃん！
I am White Prinyan-nyan!
推しピのスマイルまで何マイル！？
How many miles to my fave's smile!?
世界の果てまで狂わせて！
Drive me crazy to the ends of the earth!
ピピピ　ピピピ
Pipipi Pipipi
こっち向いて♡
Look this way ♡
ピピピ　ピピピ
Pipipi Pipipi
ハート作って♡
Make a heart ♡
ピピピ　ピピピ
Pipipi Pipipi
あんたが大将♡
You're the boss ♡
ピピピ　ピピピ
Pipipi Pipipi
愛してる♡
I love you ♡
神様助けて　また恋をしました
God help me, I've fallen in love again
（恋をしました）
(I've fallen in love)
次こそは本当の　マジのラブなんだから
Because next time is the real deal, it's serious love
ホントだよー？
I'm serious!
ピピピ　ピピピ
Pipipi Pipipi
合言葉ちょーだい♡
Give me the password ♡
ピッピッピッ
Pi-pi-pi
個性聴かせて♡
Let me hear your individuality♡
ピッピッピッ
Pi-pi-pi
3秒見つめて
Stare for 3 seconds
ピッピッピッ ×2
Pi-pi-pi x2
ファンサして〜〜
Give me some fan service~~
夢の中までも追いかけちゃうから (待って♡)
I'll chase you even into your dreams (Wait♡)
メイクも
Make-up too
ネイルも (Ah)
Nails too (Ah)
ガチ担当 (きゃぴ♡)
Your hardcore fan (Kyapi♡)
ほら可愛子セット
Look, a cute girl set
(にゃにゃにゃにゃん♡)
(Nya nya nya nyan♡)
ラブラブちゅわわ 貢いじゃう全部
Love love chu-wawa, I'll splurge everything
ここはパラダイス (ハイハイハイハイ！)
This is paradise (High high high high!)
ドキドキはわわ
Thump thump, ha-wawa
なでなでされたら
When you pat my head
もっともっと好きになっちゃう (ちゅわ♡)
I'll love you more and more (Chuwa♡)
もえもえシュワ 煽っちゃダメダメよ
Moe moe shuwa, don't tease me
羽ばたいちゃうから (ハイハイハイハイ！)
I'm gonna take flight (High high high high!)
アフターケアしてぇん♡
Give me some aftercare♡
ハートたくさん付けちゃうにゃんにゃん (にゃんにゃん♡)
I'll give you lots of hearts, nyan nyan (Nyan nyan♡)
今夜の My Tier 一番テーブル
Tonight's My Tier Number One Table
プリにゃんモード入りましたぁ〜〜！
Purinyan Mode activated~~!
世界で一番 愛してる〜 (ハイ！)
I love you most in the world~ (High!)
愛してる〜
I love you~
「あ〜〜ん 会いたかったんにゃんピ〜〜♡」
"Ah~~, I wanted to see you, nyan-pi~~♡"
「今日も頑張ってたよぉ〜 撫でて？ 褒めて〜♡」 (きゅん♡)
"I worked hard today too~ Pat me? Praise me~♡" (Kyun♡)
「ねえ ハグして？ ぎゅーって、ちゅーして？」
"Hey, hug me? Hold me tight, kiss me?"
「食べちゃうぞっ どっきゅーん♡」
"I'm gonna eat you up, dokkyuun♡"
(ハイ！) 可愛い可愛い推しピの為なら
(High!) If it's for my cute, cute oshipi
人生まるっとあげちゃいま〜す♡ (かっふー！)
I'll give you my whole life! (Kappu~!)
他の子見るとか ありえな〜i♡ (ありえな〜i♡)
Looking at other girls is impossible~♡ (Impossible~♡)
もう粗相は NO NO 許さな〜い♡ (許さな〜い♡)
No more slip-ups, NO NO, I won't forgive you~♡ (I won't forgive you~♡)
念念念念 I want you 承認欲求 暴走中
Nengyu nengyu I want you, approval desire running wild
お手製アクスタ ほっぺにちゅう メパニのスピリタス
Handmade acrylic stand, a kiss on the cheek, Mepani's spiritus
こっち見て こっち見て こっち見て こっち見て こっち見て
Look here, look here, look here, look here, look here
愛情たっぷりご満悦 3, 2, 1, よいしょ〜！
Full of love and satisfaction, 3, 2, 1, Heave-ho!
離れないよ もう推しピのものだもん♡
I won't leave, I'm already my oshipi's property♡
だから今日も頑張るにゃん♡
So I'll work hard today too, nyan♡
女の子はね…「可愛い」の数だけ
You know, girls... for every 'cute' they get
可愛くなれるんだにゃん！
They become that much cuter, nyan!
ラブラブちゅわわ 捧げます全部
Love love chu-wawa, I'll offer everything
ここはパラダイス (ハイハイハイハイ！)
This is paradise (High high high high!)
ドキドキはわわ
Thump thump, ha-wawa
ハグハグされたら
When you hug me tight
ずっとずっと好きになっちゃう (ずっとずっと)
I'll love you forever and ever (Forever and ever)
あれあれ どして そっぽ向いちゃうの？
Oh my, why are you turning away?
あの子のせいだよね？ (ハイハイハイハイ！)
It's because of that girl, isn't it? (High high high high!)
溢れる恋模様♡
Overflowing love patterns♡
ハートたくさん付けちゃうにゃんにゃん (にゃんにゃん♡)
I'll give you lots of hearts, nyan nyan (Nyan nyan♡)
ピッピッピッ
Pi-pi-pi
こっち向いて ピッピッピッ
Look this way, Pi-pi-pi
歯磨きさせて ピッピッピッ
Let me brush your teeth, Pi-pi-pi
ピッピッピッ ×2
Pi-pi-pi x2
ホクロ数えて ピッピッピッ
Count my moles, Pi-pi-pi
まだまだいける ピッピッピッ
I can still go, Pi-pi-pi
挙式結婚しよー♡ ピッピッピッ
Let's have a wedding and get married♡ Pi-pi-pi
お水おいしい？ ピッピッピッ
Is the water tasty? Pi-pi-pi
夢を見たいの ピッピッピッ
I want to see a dream, Pi-pi-pi
愛してる
I love you
愛してる♡
I love you♡
丘を越えて 山を越えて 谷を越えてゆくんだ
Over the hills, over the mountains, across the valleys we go
川を越えて 海を越えて 空を越えてゆくんだ
Over the rivers, over the seas, across the sky we go
雨上がりの空 虹を描いて 皆に会いに行くよ
In the post-rain sky, drawing a rainbow, I'm going to see everyone
(皆に会いに行くよ)
(I'm going to see everyone)
大切なのは 僕でいること 間違いだらけの毎日も
What's important is being myself, even in days full of mistakes
(間違いだらけの毎日も)
(Even in days full of mistakes)
手と手をつないで 目と目を合わせて どこまでも歩こう
Holding hand in hand, looking eye to eye, let's walk anywhere
(どこまでも歩こう)
(Let's walk anywhere)
おサルさんのロンド キリンさんのロンド
The monkey's rondo, the giraffe's rondo
ウサギさんのロンド 気がつけば僕も
The rabbit's rondo, before I knew it, I was too
小鳥たちのロンド 子犬たちのロンド
The little birds' rondo, the puppies' rondo
子猫たちのロンド 笑顔で歌うよ
The kittens' rondo, I'll sing with a smile
朝を越えて 昼を越えて 夜を越えてゆくんだ
Past the morning, past the noon, through the night we go
雲を越えて 星を越えて 星を越えてゆくんだ
Past the clouds, past the stars, past the stars we go
星空の下に 浮かべた涙 皆に会いに行くよ
Tears floating under the starry sky, I'm going to see everyone
(皆に会いに行くよ)
(I'm going to see everyone)
大人になれば わかるはずなのに 悩み事ばかり 増えてゆく
I should understand once I'm an adult, but my worries only keep increasing
(悩み事ばかり 増えてゆく)
(My worries only keep increasing)
そんな時には 空を見上げて 皆と一緒に歌いながら
At times like that, look up at the sky, and while singing together with everyone
(皆と一緒に歌いながら)
(While singing together with everyone)
お医者さんのロンド
Doctor's Rondo
大工さんのロンド
Carpenter's Rondo
八百屋さんのロンド
Greengrocer's Rondo
気がつけば僕も
Before I knew it, I too...
山田さんのロンド
Yamada's Rondo
田中さんのロンド
Tanaka's Rondo
鈴木さんのロンド
Suzuki's Rondo
笑顔で歌うよ
I'll sing with a smile!
小人さんのロンド
Little person's Rondo
巨人さんのロンド
Giant's Rondo
宇宙人ロンド
Alien's Rondo
気がつけば僕も
Before I knew it, I too...
寂しがりのロンド
Lonely person's Rondo
忘れん坊のロンド
Forgetful person's Rondo
照れ屋さんのロンド
Shy person's Rondo
笑顔で歌うよ
I'll sing with a smile!
お母さんのロンド
Mother's Rondo
お父さんのロンド
Father's Rondo
お姉ちゃんのロンド
Big sister's Rondo
気がつけば僕も
Before I knew it, I too...
お婆ちゃんのロンド
Grandmother's Rondo
お爺ちゃんのロンド
Grandfather's Rondo
君と僕のロンド
You and my Rondo
皆で歌えば
If everyone sings...
世界は回って
The world goes round...
笑顔になれるよ
And we can smile.
期待してすぐに諦めて
Hoping for it, but giving up right away
曖昧な答えに流されては
Being swept away by vague answers
自分だけ置いて行かれるような
Feeling like I'm the only one being left behind
そんなイメージが胸を突つく夜だ
It's a night where such images poke at my chest
覚えてるような　覚えていないような
As if I remember, but then again, as if I don't
憧れた記憶を彷徨うよ
I wander through memories I yearned for
僕は君のために
I am for you
君は僕のために
You are for me
生まれたならちょっと嬉しいね
If we were born for each other, it would be a bit nice
気付いたら君色に染まってるような
Before I realized it, I seemed to be dyed in your color
何気ない言葉で汚して欲しい
I want you to stain me with casual words
ずっとわかんないフリを続けてきたんだ
I've been pretending not to understand for a long time
この時が来るまで
Until this moment came
もしかして君と釣り合ってないかな？
Maybe I'm not a good match for you?
そんな不安もたまによぎるけれど
Such anxieties cross my mind sometimes, but...
いつも困らせてばかりでごめんね
I'm sorry for always causing trouble
「あぁ～、好きだよ」好きだよって伝えたい
"Ah~, I love you." I want to tell you that I love you.
傷つけないように言葉を探しても
Even if I look for words so as not to hurt you
空回り気持ちに急かされて
I'm rushed by feelings that are going in circles
ねえ間違ってるようなこれで合ってるような
Hey, it feels wrong, but it also feels right
二人の答えずっとよろしくね
Let's keep our answer together forever
気付いたら君色に染まってるような
Before I realized it, I seemed to be dyed in your color
何気ない言葉で汚して欲しい
I want you to stain me with casual words
ずっとわかんないフリを続けてきたんだ
I've been pretending not to understand for a long time
この時が来るまで
Until this moment came
もしかして君と釣り合ってないかな？
Maybe I'm not a good match for you?
そんな不安もたまによぎるけれど
Such anxieties cross my mind sometimes, but...
いつも困らせてばかりでごめんね
I'm sorry for always causing trouble
「あぁ～、好きだよ」好きだよって伝えたい
"Ah~, I love you." I want to tell you that I love you.
好きだよ、好きだよって伝えたい
I want to tell you that I love you, I love you.
はーい！ということで
Okay! And so...
なんか、あれ？
Wait, what?
白上...記憶がないんですが...
Shirakami... I have no memory of this...
あれ？白上ソロ曲歌ったっけ？
Wait? Did Shirakami sing a solo song?
なんか急に頭が痛くなって、なんか...
My head suddenly started hurting, and...
ちょっと楽しかったんですけどね
It was really fun though.
あれ？白上「ドレミファロンド」歌ってない？
Huh? Shirakami didn't sing "Doremi Pha Rondo"?
歌ってないからさ、アキちゃんがさ、「ドレミファロンド」歌っててさ
Since she didn't, Aki-chan was singing "Doremi Pha Rondo"...
白上、何をしていたんだろうか？
What was Shirakami doing then?
いや、それはぜひね、あの... 何やってたんだろう？
Well, that's definitely... what was I doing?
大人たちに聞いてみてね。大人たち！
Ask the adults about that! The adults!
大人たちにね。ということでね。ということで...
Ask the adults. Anyway, moving on...
台本には「ブリにゃモードピッピピのピ」って書いてあるんですけど
The script says "Prin-nya-mode Pippipi-no-Pi"...
歌ったかな？歌ったのかしら、白上は。
Did I sing that? Did Shirakami sing that?
アキぜは歌ったよ！歌ったの！
Aki-ze sang it! I sang it!
歌ったの！歌った記憶あるよね、なんか。
You sang it! I have a memory of it somehow.
なんか白上がプリンセスだと思ったのに...
I thought Shirakami was the princess...
...なんか別の姫に奪われていた！
...but she was taken by another princess!
姫？姫ってこと？そんな、おかしいわ。
A princess? Is that it? No way!
まあまあ、元気出しなよ。
Now, now, cheer up.
元気出す。でもアキちゃんとの「君色に染まる」までに復活できてよかった。
I'll cheer up. I'm glad I recovered before "Kimi-iro ni Somaru" with Aki-chan.
おかえり、おかえり。よかったよかった。
Welcome back, welcome back. I'm glad.
まあまあ、いつでもね。はい、「ドレミファロンド」歌わせてもらったんですけど。
Anyway, I got to sing "Doremi Pha Rondo".
ねえ、めっちゃよかった。
It was really great.
いや、でもちょっと、このね、6周年だし、思いもあり選ばせてもらった曲なんだけど。
Since it's our 6th anniversary, I chose this song with a lot of feelings.
あ、そうなんだ。
Oh, is that so?
ロンドでね、一歩ずつこう歩んでいくみたいなところが、マイペースでね、アキローズは活動してるんだけど。
Walking step by step in a rondo... Akirose has been active at her own pace.
みんなもマイペースでもいいんだよ、みたいなそんなメッセージを込めて歌わせていただきました。
I sang it with the message that everyone can go at their own pace too.
エモすぎる！エモすぎる！これからもついていくんだね。
That's so emotional! I'll keep following you!
ついてきて！みんなで行こうね！
Come with me! Let's go together!
ピッピピ！ピッピピ！ついてきな、ちゃん。
Pippipi! Pippipi! Follow me, guys.
で、そしてね、「君色に染まる」は、白上が提案したんだよね、アキちゃんとね。
And I suggested "Kimi-iro ni Somaru" to Aki-chan.
そうそうそう！
Yes, exactly!
なんか、いいなと思って。
I thought it would be nice.
ねえ、可愛いキュンソングで。そう、キュンソングで。
It's a cute "kyun" song. Yes, a "kyun" song.
今回のなんかちょっとお姫様みたいにいいかな、みたいな。
I thought it would be good, like a princess this time.
ねえ、そう、好きだよって伝えたい。
I wanted to convey my love!
ねえ、とっても可愛かった。よかったですか、皆さん。
It was so cute! How was it, everyone?
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
ね、コメントで「サザエ」って言われてるよ。サザエさん。ピッピピ。
Look, the comments say "Sazae"! Sazae-san. Pippipi.
みんな、違う！みんなファミリーになろうよ、じゃあ。
No, everyone! Let's all become a family then.
みんな一家になればいい。バフボコになればいい。
Everyone should just become one big family.
それはそれでいいかもしれないね。
That might be nice in its own way.
ということで、せっかくなんでね、撮影もね、したいなと思ってまして。
Since we're here, I'd like to take some photos.
お城をバックに、二人で。しかもブルーの衣装ですしね。
With the castle in the background. We're in blue outfits too.
ということで、可愛い写真を撮りますか。可愛い写真。イエーイ！
Let's take some cute photos then! Cute photos. Yay!
記念にピッ。キュン。
Snapshot for the memory. Kyun.
キュンキュン！はい、皆さん撮れてましたか？
Kyun kyun! Did you all get it?
君色に染めてくれるかな？あ、染めてくれるかな？
Will you dye me in your color? Will you?
恥ずかしいな、なんか。君色に。
This is kind of embarrassing. In your color.
おじ。どうかな。
My, my. How was that?
あと何かポーズないかな？パッと思い付かない？いや。
Any other poses? Anyone have ideas? No?
もう全て持っていかれて、白上のソロ曲... 持っていかれた！記憶がズタズタ。
I lost everything to my solo song... My memory is in tatters.
じゃあ二人で、こう、こ、こう、こうして... あ、いい。
Let's do this together, like this... Oh, nice.
なんか「ててわ」？どうかしら。
Is this "Te-te-wa"? How's this?
「ててわ」の、どっちを選ぶ、みたいなそういう。
Like choosing which "Te-te-wa" to pick.
君はどっちを選ぶんだい？どっちも、って言ってる。
Which one will you choose? They say both.
贅沢者め！二人は贅沢者め！でもハート作って、ハート。
Greedy people! You greedy ones! But make a heart.
はー、ハート、はー。
He-heart, hah.
ここ、こう、これ、うん。
Like this, here, yeah.
やっぱこれになるんだ。これになっちゃうね、やっぱり。
It ends up being this. It really does.
可愛いのホントに撮れた。これで大丈夫ですか。
We got some really cute ones. Is that okay?
ガオーバージョンもやって、ほら。白上はこうやって、アキちゃんは...
Do the "Gao" version too! Like this for me, and for you...
これがやはり正解なのかもしれない。
This might be the right way after all.
正解なのかな。伝統芸か。ねえ。
Is it? Traditional art? Yeah.
皆さん撮ってくれましたかね。ハッシュタグでもぜひ呟いてください。
Did everyone get them? Please tweet with the hashtag!
いっぱい盛り上げてくれると嬉しい。では、次は、4人で歌う曲となっております。
We'd be happy if you hype it up! Next is a song by the four of us.
ちょっと向こうのお城に、行こうかと思います。お城に。
We're going to head over to that castle over there.
レッツ、レッツ、ゴー！ゴー！帰ろ、帰ろ。
Let's, let's, go! Go! Let's go back.
輝夜の城で踊りたい
Kaguya no Shiro de Odoritai
おいで おいで 誘惑のたそがれ
Come here, come here, into the twilight of temptation
おいでよ おいで かぐやの城へ
Come along, come here, to Kaguya's castle
出会い あやつる ミステリー
A mystery that manipulates encounters
いけない ベラドンナ
You shouldn't, belladonna
踊ろ 踊ろ
Let's dance, let's dance
終わらない遊び
The never-ending play
踊ろよ 踊ろ
Dance, let's dance
かぐやの城で
In Kaguya's castle
夜空を切りとる レーザービーム
Laser beams cutting through the night sky
私だけ 見てよ
Look only at me
まばゆい星が照らす想い
Thoughts illuminated by dazzling stars
今宵の夢よ 永遠に
May tonight's dream last forever
今宵の夢で踊りたい
I want to dance in tonight's dream
今宵の夢よ永遠に
Tonight's dream forever
明日のことは忘れたいの
I want to forget about tomorrow
私は赤い薔薇の姫よ
I am the red rose princess
優しくさらわれたい
I want to be gently whisked away
そっと囁いて
Whisper softly
意味ありげに目をそらす
Avoid eye contact suggestively
あなたは白い月の騎士
You are the white moon knight
触れた手がまだ熱い
The hand that touched is still hot
のがさずに抱きしめて
Hold me tight and don't let go
この奇跡を恋と呼ぶのね
This miracle is called love, isn't it
おいで おいで 情熱でダンスあげ
Come on, come on, dance with passion
おいでよ おいで かぐやの城へ
Come, come to Kaguya's Castle
迷いも飲み込むアン・ドゥ・トロワ
Un, deux, trois, swallowing up even hesitation
手も足もパッショネイト
Passionate from head to toe
踊ろ 踊ろ 止まらない遊び
Let's dance, let's dance, a non-stop amusement
踊ろや 踊ろ かぐやの城で
Let's dance, let's dance, in Kaguya's Castle
星座が織りなすピカピカ私を
For the sparkling me woven by the constellations,
待ってて
please wait for me
きらめく星に誓う心
My heart swears to the twinkling stars
儚い夢でいいわ
A fleeting dream is just fine
明日は 明日の風が吹くの
Tomorrow, the winds of tomorrow will blow
私は黒い薔薇の姫よ
I am the black rose princess
激しくさらわれたい
I want to be intensely whisked away
だから微笑んで
So, please smile
追いかけてと目が誘う
My eyes invite you to chase me
あなたも黒い月の騎士
You too are the black moon knight
瞳の奥は熱い
The depths of your eyes are hot
つかまえて抱きしめて
Catch me and hold me tight
この奇跡は恋を呼ぶのね
This miracle calls for love, doesn't it
一緒に行こう！
Let's go together!
気づいてよ！
Notice me!
他の人を見ちゃいや！
Don't look at anyone else!
私だけを見て！
Look only at me!
後悔するわよ！
You'll regret it!
楽しもう！
Let's have fun!
早くしなさいよ！
Hurry up!
いじわるですね
You're mean
いいの？
Is it okay?
私は赤い薔薇の姫よ
I am the red rose princess
優しくさらわれたい
I want to be gently whisked away
そっと囁いて
Whisper softly
意味ありげに目をそらす
Avoid eye contact suggestively
あなたは白い月の騎士
You are the white moon knight
触れた手がまだ熱い
The hand that touched is still hot
のがさずに抱きしめて
Hold me tight and don't let go
この奇跡を恋と呼ぶのね
This miracle is called love, isn't it
晩餐歌
Dinner Song
作詞・作曲:tuki.
Lyrics/Composition: tuki.
君を泣かすから だから一緒には居れないな
Since I make you cry, that's why we can't be together
君を泣かすから 早く忘れて欲しいんだ
Since I make you cry, I want you to forget me soon
人間だからね たまには違うものも食べたいね
We're only human, so sometimes we want to eat something different
君を泣かすから そう君を泣かすから
Since I make you cry, yes, since I make you cry
でも味気ないないないんだよね
But it's just so bland and boring
会いたくなんだよね 君以外会いたくないんだよね
I start wanting to see you, I don't want to see anyone but you
なんて勝手だんね
How selfish of me
大体曖昧なんだよね 愛の存在証明なんて
Everything's so ambiguous, like a proof of love's existence
君が教えてくれないか
Won't you tell me?
何十回の夜を過ごしたって 得られぬような
Even after spending dozens of nights, it's something I can't obtain
「愛してる」を並べてみて
Try lining up all those 'I love you's
何十回の夜を過ごしたって 得られぬような
Even after spending dozens of nights, it's something I can't obtain
最高のフルコースを頂戴
Give me the finest full-course meal
君を泣かすから 君を泣かすから きっと一生は...
Since I make you cry, since I make you cry, surely a lifetime...
無理だよね
It's impossible, isn't it?
君を泣かすから
Because I make you cry,
胸がとても痛むんだ
my chest hurts so much.
人間だからね
Because we're human,
たまには分かり合えなくなって
sometimes we can't understand each other,
君を泣かすから
because I make you cry,
また君を泣かすから
because I make you cry again.
でも自信がないないないんだよね
But I have no, no, no confidence, you know.
変わりたくないないないんだよね
I don't want to change, no, no, no.
君以外会いたくないんだよね
I don't want to see anyone but you,
なんて勝手だね
how selfish of me.
大体曖昧だったよね
It was mostly vague,
愛の存在証明なんて
the proof of love's existence.
君がそこに居るのにね
Even though you're right there.
何百回の夜を過ごしたって
No matter how many hundreds of nights pass,
得られぬような
that unattainable...
愛してるを並べてみて
...'I love you's, try lining them up.
何百回の夜を過ごしたって
No matter how many hundreds of nights pass,
得られぬような
that unattainable...
最高級のフルコースを頂戴
...highest-grade full course, please give it to me.
離れないで傍に居てくれたのは
The one who stayed by my side without leaving was...
結局君一人だったよね
...you alone in the end, weren't you?
涙のスパイスは君の胸に
The spice of tears in your heart...
残ってしまうだろうけど
...will probably remain, but...
何千回の夜を過ごしたって
No matter how many thousands of nights pass,
得られぬような
that unattainable...
愛してるを並べるから
...'I love you's, I'll line them up.
何千回の夜を過ごしたって
No matter how many thousands of nights pass,
得られぬような
that unattainable...
最高級のフルコースを
...highest-grade full course...
何万回の夜を過ごしたって
No matter how many tens of thousands of nights pass,
忘れぬような
that unforgettable...
愛してるを並べるから
...'I love you's, I'll line them up.
何万回の夜を過ごしたって
No matter how many tens of thousands of nights pass,
忘れぬような
that unforgettable...
最高級のフルコースを頂戴
...highest-grade full course, please give it to me.
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world,
そういう扱い心得て
make sure you know how to treat me like that.
ワールドイズマイン
World is Mine
作詞・作曲 ryo
Lyrics & Composition: ryo
その一 いつもと違う髪形に気がつくこと
Number one: notice when my hairstyle is different from usual.
その二 ちゃんと靴まで見ること いいね？
Number two: look properly all the way down to my shoes, okay?
その三 私の一言には三つの言葉で返事すること
Number three: reply to my every word with three of your own.
わかったら右手がお留守なのを何とかして！
If you understand, do something about my right hand being empty!
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything.
キミに心から思って欲しいの
I want you to think from the bottom of your heart...
かわいいって
...that I'm cute.
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world.
気がついて ねえねえ
Notice me, hey, hey.
待たせるなんて論外よ
Keeping me waiting is out of the question.
私を誰だと思ってるの？
Who do you think I am?
もうなんだか
Oh, honestly...
甘いものが食べたい！
I want to eat something sweet!
今すぐによ
Right now!
おーっ！
Oh!
チェックワンツー！
Check one two!
欠点？かわいいの間違いでしょ
Flaws? You must mean 'cute' instead.
文句は許しませんの
I won't allow any complaints.
あのね、私の話ちゃんと聞いてる？ちょっと！
Listen, are you listening to what I'm saying? Hey!
あ、それとね 白いお馬さん 決まってるでしょ？
Ah, and also, a white horse is a given, right?
迎えに来て
Come pick me up.
わかったらかしずいて手を取って「おひめさま」
If you understand, kneel down, take my hand, and say 'Princess'.
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything.
でもね 少しくらい叱ってくれたっていいのよ
But you know, it's okay to scold me just a little bit.
世界で私だけのおうじさま
My one and only prince in the world,
気がついて ほらほら
notice me, look, look.
おててが空いてます
My hand is free.
うーっ！
Uhh!
...て 無愛想な王子様
...unfriendly prince,
もう どうして！
Oh, why?!
気がついてよ早く
Notice me soon,
ぜったい君は
You definitely
分かってない
don't understand,
分かってないわ...
you don't understand...
いちごの載ったショートケーキ
Strawberry shortcake,
こだわりたまごのとろけるプリン
melting pudding made with special eggs.
みんな みんな 我慢します
I'll hold back on all of them,
わがままな子だと思わないで
so don't think I'm a selfish girl.
私だってやればできるもん
I can do it if I try,
あとで後悔するわよ
you'll regret it later.
当然です！だって私は
Of course! Because I'm
世界で一番おひめさま
the number one princess in the world.
ちゃんと見ててよね
Watch me properly,
どこかに行っちゃうよ？
or I'll go somewhere else.
ふいに抱きしめられた
Suddenly being hugged,
急にそんな えっ？
so suddenly, eh?
「惹かれる、危ないよ」
"You'll get run over, it's dangerous,"
そう言ってそっぽ向く君
you say that and look away.
こっちのが危ないわよ
This is more dangerous!
先輩の！
Senpai's!
バカーー！
Idiot!
さよならプリンセス 宙に舞っている
Goodbye Princess, dancing in the air.
独り沈む その姿は華やかだ
Sinking alone, that figure is elegant.
魅惑のハッピーエンド
An enchanting happy ending,
私とさよならだ
it's goodbye to me.
さよならプリンセス 作詞・作曲 Kai
Sayonara Princess. Lyrics & Composition: Kai
鏡の中 独り縛られて
Bound alone inside the mirror,
頭の中 逃げ回る毎日です
every day I'm running around inside my head.
ずっと ずっと だって私変われないし
Always, always, because I can't change,
夢もないし 愚痴もないし
I have no dreams, no complaints,
つまらないし 可愛くもないし
I'm boring and not cute,
分からないし 生き甲斐ないし
I don't understand and have no purpose,
不意に気づいてる まるで
suddenly I realized, it's as if
指輪が首輪になっていたんだ
the ring had become a collar.
壊れた大人の愛情なんだ
It's the broken affection of an adult,
期待を捨てた 私のことなんて気にしないでね
don't worry about me, who has cast aside expectations.
さよならプリンセス 宙に舞っている
Goodbye Princess, dancing in the air.
独り浮かぶ その姿は華やかだ
Floating alone, that figure is elegant.
魅惑のハッピーエンド
An enchanting happy ending,
私とさよならだ
it's goodbye to me.
間抜けなプリンセス 過去にバイバイだ
Stupid princess, say bye-bye to the past.
この際何も 全てを燃やしてしまおう
Let's just burn everything at this point.
このまま宙を泳いで
Just keep swimming through the air,
あの星になれたら
if only I could become that star.
私 私とさよならだ
Me, it's goodbye to myself.
心の穴 妬み渦巻いた
The hole in my heart, swirling with envy,
体の中 空回り毎日です
every day is just spinning my wheels inside my body.
ずっと ずっと だってあなた頭いいし
Always, always, because you're smart,
変わらないし 足長いし
you don't change, your legs are long,
面白いし 顔も可愛いし
you're funny and your face is cute,
さりげないし 仕方ないし
you're casual, it can't be helped,
溢れるオーラは まるで
the overflowing aura is as if
キラキラ輝く安定剤
a sparkling, shining stabilizer.
メロメロ私は面目ないね
I'm head over heels, I'm so ashamed.
古き昨日の 私のことなんて探さないでね
Don't look for me, who belongs to the old yesterday.
さよならプリンセス 愛に寄っている
Goodbye Princess, drawing closer to love.
独り浮かぶ その姿は鮮やかだ
Floating alone, that figure is vivid.
理想のハッピーエンド
An ideal happy ending,
私とさよならだ
it's goodbye to me.
さよならプリンセス 全てバイバイだ
Goodbye Princess, say bye-bye to everything.
廻る廻る 幸せに絡まるほど
Turning and turning, as much as I'm entangled in happiness.
間抜けなハッピーエンド
A stupid happy ending,
可愛くなれたかな
did I become cute?
私 私は既に分かってたんだ
I, I already knew,
この世とさよならだ
it's goodbye to this world.
はぁー！すごかった！
Haa! That was amazing!
すごかったー！
It was amazing!
ねー！
Right!
ということでね
So then,
全員で歌った後にソロとユニットやりましたけど
after we all sang together, we did solos and units.
エモすぎる！
It's too emotional!
ね、良かったでしょ？
Right, it was good, right?
てか、まつり清楚担当だったわ
Wait, Matsuri was the purity rep.
ずっと清楚担当だったよね
I've always been the purity rep, right?
清楚担当だったんだ
You were the purity rep.
そうなんですよ
That's right.
今回はね、なんか今までまつりダンスとかを
This time, well, until now Matsuri usually...
結構見せる曲を選びがちだったんだけど
chose songs that really show off dancing,
まぁ、あの7年目に向けて
well, towards the 7th year...
また言えなかったよ
I couldn't say it again.
あれ？
Wait?
7年目に向けて
Towards the 7th year...
歌も頑張りたいなと思ったので
I wanted to work hard on my singing too,
ちょっと歌メインの曲にしてみたよって感じでございますね
so I tried making it a bit more of a song-focused track.
エモかったでしょ？
Wasn't it emotional?
エモかったでしょ、歌もエモかったし
It was emotional, wasn't it? The singing was emotional too.
嬉しい嬉しい、嬉しいな
I'm happy, happy, so happy.
感動したよ
I was moved.
そしてね、そのあと、はぁとちゃんが
And then, after that, Haato-chan...
はい、ワールドイズマイン！
Yes, 'World is Mine'!
あ、実はこの曲ですね、あの、まつりちゃんに選曲してもらって
Actually, this song, well, I had Matsuri-chan choose it for me.
そう、ぴったりでしょ？
Yeah, it's a perfect fit, right?
はい、ちょっとね、並んでみるんじゃない。
All right, let's try standing together.
え、今は7年目？6年目？
Wait, is this our 7th year? 6th year?
7年目。
Our 7th year.
今ね、6年目を迎えた...
We just reached our 6th year...
今6年目を迎えたんですけど...
We just reached our 6th year, but...
ちょっとね、まずね、原点に帰り...
I want to go back to our roots first...
ちょっと、まぁ、あの頃のツンケンした感じにね、戻って...
And go back to that standoffish vibe from back then...
初心を思い出そうと、いうことでね。
To remember our original intentions.
めっちゃ可愛かった！
You were so cute!
というわけよ！
That's how it is!
めっちゃ可愛かったよ、はあとちゃんって感じだった。
You were super cute, like the classic Haato-chan.
ちゃんと見てくれてたー？
Were you watching carefully?
この舞台を！
This performance!
滑る要素が急にね...
Suddenly the "slippery" element comes in...
急じゃない、とってつけたような、急じゃない！
It wasn't sudden! It wasn't forced or sudden!
そしてね、2人でね...
And then, the two of us...
そう、「さよならプリンセス」を歌いましたよ！
Right, we sang "Sayonara Princess"!
そう、これはね、やっぱお姫様っていうタイトルですから。
Yeah, since the title has "Princess" in it.
そう、プリンセスって付いてるからね、すごいちょっと安直...
Yeah, because it says "Princess", it was a bit simplistic...
なんだけど、でもさ、やっぱ可愛い系の曲で...
But still, it's such a cute song...
なんかちょっとこう、ポップな感じでね。
With a bit of a pop feel to it.
なんかポップ担当と可愛い担当って感じなんでね、ぴったりだったかなと思いますね。
I think it was a perfect fit for the pop and cute roles.
ぴったりの選曲でしたね。
It was a perfect song choice.
ちなみにこのペアはね、あの、グーチョキパ... グーチョキパじゃない。
By the way, this pair was decided by... not Rock-Paper-Scissors.
グッパ、グッパ、グッパで合わせみたいな感じでやりましたね。
We used "Gu-pa" (Rock or Palm) to split the teams.
それはさ、言わなくていいじゃん、わざわざ！
You didn't have to say that out loud!
それで合わさったはあとちゃんペアと向こうになるっていう。
And that's how I ended up paired with Haato-chan.
あえてね、2人でさ、仲良くてやったってことにしとこ、じゃあ。
Let's just say we paired up because we're good friends.
もういいじゃん、なんでなんで、ごめん！
Fine, whatever! Why? I'm sorry!
仲良しですのでね、やりました。
We did it because we're close friends.
はい、ということで、あの2人もやってたんだけど、撮影会をちょっとね、やりたくない？
Anyway, the others did it too, but don't you want to do a photoshoot?
やりたいやりたい！
I do, I do!
あれ、でもさ、ほら、あれは？てつ、てつ、てつ...
Wait, what about... Tetsu, tetsu, tetsu...
何何？
What, what?
また間違えた！やだ！
I messed up again! No way!
あれカグヤって読むんだよ。
That's read as "Kaguya."
何何？
What is it?
そうそう、カグヤ。リハでもなんかテツテツとか言ってて...
Right, Kaguya. She was saying "Tetsu Tetsu" during rehearsal too...
カグヤね。
Kaguya, right.
ほら、踊ってみたの振り返りしたいなと思ったけどさ。
I wanted to look back on the "Dance Cover"...
そう、カグヤもめっちゃ良かったですね。
Yeah, Kaguya was really good too.
みんなのね、セリフパート。
Everyone's spoken parts.
清楚が光ってたけど、みんなのね、セリフパートがもう本当に個性が光ってました。
Their purity was shining, but their personalities really stood out in the spoken lines.
アキロゼのセクシーさやばかったよね。
Aki-rose's sexiness was incredible, wasn't it?
やばかったね、エロかった、エロいとか言っちゃダメだよ、公式で。
It was crazy, so sexy. You shouldn't say "erotic" on an official stream!
ということで、撮影会行きましょうか。
Anyway, let's start the photoshoot.
みんな何が欲しいの？
What pose do you all want?
ハートポーズ一旦やっとく？
Should we do a heart pose first?
2人はこれだったけど、私達はちゃんと...
The other two did this, but we'll do it properly...
なんでだよ、リハでちゃんとやったよ！
What do you mean? We did it right in rehearsal!
やめて、押さないで！
Stop it, don't push me!
はい、ちゃんとやって、せーの...
Okay, let's do it right. One, two...
ハート！
Heart!
ちょっと割れてる、ねぇ、何で！
It's a bit broken! Hey, why?!
次何にする？
What's next?
まつりちゃんはまつりちゃん、わっしょいポーズ？
For Matsuri-chan, maybe the "Washoi" pose?
わっしょいポーズって何？こんな感じ？
What's the "Washoi" pose? Like this?
そう！いいじゃん！こっちがいい？どっちがいいよ。
Yes! That's good! This way? Which way do you like?
わっしょーい！
Washoi!
せっかくさ、センターでお城がいい感じに見えるから...
Since the castle looks so good from the center...
あ、プリンセスっぽい感じのポーズで行こう。
Oh, let's do a princess-like pose.
ポーズ！あ、分かった、これ間にオタくんが入るとね...
Pose! Oh, I see, if an "Otaku" stands between us...
そうそう、どっちを選びますか？こっち？どっちを選ぶの？
Exactly! Which one will you choose? This one? Which one?
ハーレムじゃんこれ！
This is a harem!
めっちゃいいめっちゃいい！すごい！ツイートしてね、このタグで。
So good, so good! Amazing! Please tweet it with the tag.
え、待って、むせた！
Wait, I choked!
バカバカバカ、次行くぞ、次行くぞ！
Dummy, dummy! Moving on, moving on!
ということで戻りますね、次も頑張って盛り上がっていきましょう！
Alright, let's head back. Let's keep the energy up for the next part!
すみません皆さん、連れて行くんで、失礼します！
Sorry everyone, I'll take her with me. Excuse us!
リハでやったことないのにやっちゃった！
I did something we never even tried in rehearsal!
Plasmagic Seasons!
輝く夜空 瞬く星を追って
Chasing the twinkling stars in the shining night sky
春風 君を乗せて 熱い夏が迎えるよ
Carrying you on the spring breeze, a hot summer awaits
色めく秋が 背中を押したら
When the colorful autumn gives a gentle push
まっ白 冬吹きらり 巡りゆくストーリー
Pure white winter sparkles, a story that comes around
何もわからない 一歩進んで
Knowing nothing, taking one step forward
やっとここまで たどり着けたね
We've finally made it this far, haven't we?
まちはピンクずっと 素敵なステージ
The town is pink, a wonderful stage forever
一番に 絶対見せてあげるよ
I'll definitely show you the best view
行こう Smile! Smile!
Let's go! Smile! Smile!
Catch up future!
無邪気に回る季節が 世界を
The innocently turning seasons will change the world
駆ける五等星
...soaring five-star constellation.
夢のような日々へと
To days like a dream
光れ Bright! Bright! Light up future!
Shine Bright! Bright! Light up future!
僕らが一等星
We are the brightest stars
そうさ 照らし続けよう
That's right, let's keep on shining
スポットライトは ついたばかり
The spotlight has only just come on
赤らむ 頬を撫でる イルミネーション
Illumination caressing blushing cheeks
言葉は 言えずとも 弾ける万華鏡
Even without words, a kaleidoscope bursts
幸せ いっぱい 注ぐ このグラス
Pouring happiness into this glass
鳴らして キラリ 染まるよ
Ring it out, and let it sparkle
真っ白な気持ち
With pure white feelings
12時の鐘 なんか忘れちゃって
Just forget about the midnight bell
ずっと解けない 魔法 かけよう
Let's cast a magic spell that never breaks
ときめきだして
Start to feel your heart throb
そうさ 胸躍る時間を
That's right, the time that makes your heart dance...
...贈るから
...is what I'll give to you
絶対ついておいでよ
Definitely come follow me
届け Spark! Spark! Pop up future!
Reach out, Spark! Spark! Pop up future!
いまを駆ける五つ星
Five stars soaring through the present
世界も巻き込んで 賑やかに遊ぼう
Let's involve the world and play lively
ずっと Flash! Flash! Plasmagic up future!
Always Flash! Flash! Plasmagic up future!
目も眩むシチュエーション
A dazzling situation
まだ踊り足りないでしょ？
You haven't danced enough yet, right?
アンコールの ずっとずっと先まで
Until far, far beyond the encore
楽しむ気持ちさえ 持ってきたら
If you just bring your feelings of enjoyment
きっと誰もが主役になれるよ
Surely everyone can be the main character
ハメ外した 笑顔も さらけ出して
Reveal even your smiles that let loose
もっとSTEP もっとJUMP
More STEP, more JUMP
終わらない この世界を
In this never-ending world...
一緒に遊び尽くそう
...let's play to our hearts' content together
響け Clap! Clap! Let's sing future!
Ring out, Clap! Clap! Let's sing future!
このメロディが 終わっても
Even if this melody ends...
決して今日だけの 思い出にはしないよ
...I'll never let it be just a memory of today
行こう Smile! Smile! Catch up future!
Let's go, Smile! Smile! Catch up future!
無邪気に回る季節が
The seasons that turn innocently...
世界を駆け巡って
...roam around the world
夢のような日々へと
To days like a dream
光れ Bright! Bright! Light up future!
Shine Bright! Bright! Light up future!
僕らが一等星
We are the brightest stars
そうさ 照らし続けよう
That's right, let's keep on shining
スポットライトは 終わらない
The spotlight never ends
はい、ということで！
Alright, and so!
「Plasmagic Seasons!」でございましたー！
That was "Plasmagic Seasons!"
イェーイ！
Yay!
皆様、あの状態からよく歌って踊れたなー！
Everyone, I can't believe you could sing and dance after that!
切り替え大事！
The switch is important!
切り替えね！
The switch, right?
めっちゃ焦ってたのに！
Even though you were panicking so much!
こっち戻ってきたと思ったらビシッと！
I thought you just came back, then suddenly you're on point!
切り替えがすごかった。
The switch was amazing.
ちゃんとできたよ。
We did it properly.
それがスーパーアイドルか。
Is that what a super idol is?
これがスーパーアイドル！
This is a super idol!
失礼いたしました、皆様。
Sorry about that, everyone.
切り替えほんますごかった、ちゃま。
Your switch was really amazing, Chama.
ということで、Plasmagic Seasons、ちょっと久しぶりにね、歌って踊りましたな、この曲も。
And so, we sang and danced to "Plasmagic Seasons" for the first time in a while.
はい。相変わらず楽しい楽曲でございました。
Yes. It was a fun song, as always.
はい。ではね、なんと次が最後の曲になってしまうんですけども…
Yes. Well then, it's actually time for the final song...
えー！？
Ehh?!
その前に！我々からのお知らせがございますよ！
Before that! We have an announcement!
はい！
Yes!
なんと！我々ホロライブ1期生活動6周年の周年、1期生のね、全員のセットの、何て言ったらいいんだろう、ま、グッズが出ます！グッズ！
Actually! To celebrate our 6th anniversary, we're releasing a set of... well, how should I put it... goods for all the 1st gen members!
イェーイ！可愛いー！
Yay! So cute!
ホロライブ1期生 6周年記念
Hololive 1st Generation 6th Anniversary
ホロライブ1期生 6周年記念！
Hololive 1st Gen 6th Anniversary!
ということでラインナップ見ていきましょう、こちら！ドドドドドン！
So let's take a look at the lineup! Here it is! Ta-da!
アクリルスタンド (全4種)
Acrylic Stands (All 4 Types)
こちらですね。まずは、アクリルスタンドです！
Here they are. First, acrylic stands!
ちょこんと。
Just sitting there.
はい。こちらですね、今回みんなプリンセスということで。
Yes. For these, everyone is a princess.
それぞれのちょっとね、ドレスを…
And for each of the dresses...
ポージングしてる。
They're posing.
もっ、こうなって、こうなって、足クロスしてる。
Like, this, and this, and legs crossed.
はい。プリンセス衣装でのアクリルスタンド、ご用意させていただきました。
Yes. We've prepared acrylic stands featuring our princess outfits.
いわふわはる先生に描いていただきました。ありがとうございます。
They were illustrated by Iwafuwaharu-sensei. Thank you very much.
可愛いです。どうですか？
They're cute. What do you think?
みんななんか違うよね、ドレス。
Everyone's dress is a bit different.
アクリルスタンド (全4種)
Acrylic Stands (4 types)
ちょっと一番際どいのがアキ・ローゼじゃない？
Isn't Akirose's the most revealing one?
アキ・ローゼじゃん！
It's Akirose!
アキ・ローゼだー！
えー、見せ方やばーい！
Wow, that way of showing it is crazy!
だよねー！
Right?!
あ、ねー、今日だけなら見せてあげる。
Ah, hey, I'll show you just for today.
やだー！
No way!
ちょっと、見て見て！
Hey, look, look!
あ、ちゃまはダメー！
Ah, Chama is no good!
だめだめだめ！見せちゃダメだよ！
No, no, no! You can't show it!
なんかまつりちゃんのやつだけフワッとしてて、めちゃ可愛いよね。
Matsuri-chan's is so soft and fluffy, it's super cute.
そう、可愛い！
Yeah, so cute!
実は意外にね、あの、一番露出が少ないのがまつりなんです。
Actually, surprisingly, Matsuri has the least skin exposure.
そうそうそう、意外な清楚！
Right, right, unexpectedly wholesome!
そうなんですよ！
Exactly!
清楚担当だった？
Were you the wholesome one?
凄く可愛いんだけど！
It's so cute though!
じゃあ続いていきますか、続いてこちら！
Shall we move on? Next is this!
チェキ風カード & チェキ風カードホルダー (全4種)
Cheki-style Card & Holder (4 types)
はい、こちらチェキ風カード＆チェキ風カードホルダーでございます！
Yes, here is the Cheki-style card and Cheki-style card holder!
可愛い！オシャレ！
Cute! Stylish!
ねー、チェキはね、多分いろんな人ら出してきたと思うんだけど、
Right, I think many people have released Chekis before,
意外とチェキホルダーがないなっていうのにね、
but we noticed there aren't many Cheki holders.
気づきまして、今回併せてチェキと一緒にチェキホルダーをつけさせていただきました。
So this time, we're including a holder along with the Cheki.
今出てるのはアキロゼとはあちゃま仕様ですね。
The ones shown now are the Akirose and Haachama versions.
イェーイ！可愛い！
Yay! Cute!
これ、後ろにね、ロゴ付いてて可愛い！
The logo on the back is cute too!
ぜひぜひ使ってね！
Please use them!
そしてもう一枚どうぞ、ドドン！
And another one, please, ta-da!
はい、こちら白上とまつりちゃんでーす！
Yes, here are the Shirakami and Matsuri-chan versions!
可愛い！爽やかであり可愛い！
Cute! Refreshing and cute!
これをね、また付けてね、来年とかにあるかわからないけどイベントとかね。
You can carry this with you to future events, if there are any.
いいよねー、現場とかでね、是非使って欲しいなと思います！
It's great, I hope you use them at venues!
持ち運べるの嬉しいね。嬉しいですね。
It's nice to be able to carry it. It really is.
そしてそして次、これいいんだよなー！
And next, this one's really good!
グラス
Glass
わぁー！おしゃれ！
Wow! So stylish!
一期生グラスでございます！
It's the 1st Gen Glass!
いいね！乾杯ー！
Nice! Cheers!
これもなかなかおしゃれでね、本当に素敵なグラスになったなと思います。
This is also quite stylish, it turned out to be a really wonderful glass.
記念グッズ感凄いまんさいでいい！
It's full of that commemorative merchandise feel, I love it!
高級感漂うので是非とも、こちらも愛用していただければと思います。
It has a luxurious feel, so please make use of it.
こちらいつ出るんだ？10時か。このあと10時なのか。
When does this come out? 10 PM? Is it at 10 PM after this?
このあと10時ですか？22時に確か販売開始だったかなと思います。
10 PM after this? I believe sales start at 22:00.
よろしくお願いしまーす！お待ちしてまーす！
Please look forward to it! We'll be waiting!
まで、今回、これで一期生の、まぁ、まとめての周年グッズが出たのですが、
Now, these were the 1st Gen collective anniversary goods, but...
ま、でも毎年我々なんか個人でも出している気がするんですが、
But I feel like we also release individual ones every year...
お、まさかまさか、まさかまさか？
Oh, could it be? Could it be?
ということで、はあちゃま何それ、元気いっぱいだな、凄。スキップ、スキップ、スキップ！
And so... Haachama, what is that? You're so energetic. Skip, skip, skip!
あれスキップできない、大好き。あれスキップできない、大好き。
I can't do that skip, but I love it. I can't do it, but I love it.
ということで、はい、こちらです！しっとるー！
And so, here it is! I know this!
活動6周年記念
6th Anniversary Celebration
我々の周年個人グッズも、明日ですね、リレー配信で販売開始しようと思います！
Our individual anniversary goods will start selling tomorrow during the relay streams!
はあちゃま、これコンセプトは何ですか？
Haachama, what's the concept for this?
コンセプト！やはりはあちゃまクッキングチャンネル、かつ、
The concept! As expected, the Haachama Cooking Channel, and...
可愛いということで、クッキング✕可愛を掛け合わせました。今回よろしくお願いします！
Kawaii! So it's Cooking x Kawaii combined. Please check them out!
なるほど、怖可愛いね！怖可愛い！怖いと可愛い、いいわねー！
I see, scary-cute! Scary-cute! Scary and cute, that's good!
こちらは明日の何時から配信？
What time is the stream tomorrow?
えっと、19時半から配信します！見に来てねー！
Um, I'll be streaming from 19:30! Come watch!
販売は20時です。配信からとなっております。詳細は配信で！
Sales start at 20:00 after the stream. Details during the stream!
そしてまた20時から、はい、20時からはこちら、ドドン！
And then from 20:00... yes, from 20:00 it's this, ta-da!
はい、20時からは白上、配信させていただきます。可愛い、清楚、美しい！
Yes, I, Shirakami, will be streaming from 20:00. Cute, wholesome, beautiful!
衣装、今回もお嬢様的な感じに。最近やっとお披露目できた洋装衣装で
The outfit has a young lady vibe this time. It's the Western-style outfit I finally got to reveal.
グッズを出させていただきます！
I'll be releasing goods with it!
こちら20時から配信開始で、そこで商品紹介したあと20時30分から、
The stream starts at 20:00, and after introducing the items, from 20:30,
ホロライブの公式のストアで販売でございますので、よろしくお願いします！
they will be on sale at the official Hololive store. Thank you!
そして次、ハイ！まつりです！わー！
And next, hi! It's Matsuri! Whoo!
コンセプトは？コンセプトは「一緒にゲームしよ」って感じでございますね！
The concept? The concept is "Let's play games together"!
ニャー！ハイ！
Nya! Yes!
まつりは20時半に配信スタートで、21時に販売開始なので、よろしくお願いいたします！
My stream starts at 20:30, and sales start at 21:00. Please check it out!
あ、こーちーちゃんいいいね！いいでしょ！いいよ！
Ah, Kochi-chan looks good! Isn't it? It's great!
エロ全体気になりますけど、また詳細は明日ということで。そして続いては、
I'm curious about the sexiness, but details will be tomorrow. And moving on...
ハイハイハイハイ！イェーイ！これもまた可愛い！いい！
Hi, hi, hi, hi! Yay! This is also cute! Nice!
はい、アキロゼおねえちゃん、こちらグッズ、コンセプトは、
Yes, Akirose onee-chan's goods here. The concept is,
まあ、ちょっと普段着というか、いつものね、ちょっと
well, sort of everyday wear, showing a bit of my usual...
だらしない一面も見せちゃおうかな、みたいな、そういう感じのコンセプトになっております！
relaxed/sloppy side. That's the concept this time!
なるほどー！なるほどね！
I see! I get it!
え、こちら、21時から配信の、21時30分に発売予定してるので、
Um, the stream is from 21:00, and sales are scheduled for 21:30.
続けてリレー配信をぜひよろしくお願いします！お願いしまーす！
Please watch the relay streams! Thank you!
あ、実ははあちゃまの本当の周年なんですよ。
Oh, it's actually Haachama's real anniversary.
そう、そうだよ。
That's right, that's right.
実ははあちゃまは６月２日が、えっと周年なので是非ともお祝いしてください。
Actually, Haachama's anniversary is June 2nd, so please celebrate it.
お願いします。よろしくお願いします。
Please do. Thank you.
ということで１９時からね、また１期生ちょっとラッシュでございますがよろしくお願いします。
So, from 7 PM, it'll be a bit of a 1st Gen rush, so we look forward to it.
そして皆さん！ハッシュタグがトレンド入りしている！
And everyone! The hashtag is trending!
おおー！ありがとう！
Whoa! Thank you!
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
一杯ツイートしてね。
Please tweet a lot.
可愛いところとかスクショしてね。
Take screenshots of the cute parts.
ね、見せて。後で見るからね。
Show us. We'll look at them later.
ね、見ようね。よろしくお願いします。
Yeah, let's look. Thank you.
さて、そしてね、ま、次が最後の楽曲なんですけども。
Now, well, the next one is the last song.
何、何？何やっちゃおうかな？
What is it? What should we do?
ちょっとね、もう一つ告知がございますよね。
There's actually one more announcement, right?
まあ、まあ、ありますよね。我々からね、もう一つの告知がこちら！
Well, yeah, there is. Here's another announcement from us!
パン！
Bam!
来るか？...あれ？...来た！
Is it coming? ...Oh? ...It's here!
ホロライブ１期生オリジナル楽曲第２弾！
Hololive 1st Generation's 2nd original song!
第２弾！イエーイ！
The 2nd one! Yay!
はい、タイトルが『Secret Garden』ということで。
Yes, the title is 'Secret Garden'.
『Secret Garden』。オシャレ！
'Secret Garden'. So stylish!
え、なんかさ、カッコいい感じの第２弾、カッコいい感じがして。お披露目待ち遠しいんだけど。
Like, it feels cool for a 2nd song. I can't wait for the premiere.
ね、待ち遠しいね。ね、こちらの曲をこの後ね、ちょっとお披露目させていただこうかと思います。
Right, can't wait. We're going to premiere this song right after this.
はい！そして、楽曲の配信もですね、この後２４時から配信開始！
Yes! And the digital release starts at midnight tonight!
そしてね、ずっとホロライブの公式チャンネルで『？？？』があったと思うんですけど。
And, there's been a '???' on the official Hololive channel for a while.
こちらですね、２２時１５分からこちらの『Secret Garden』のMV公開です！
At 10:15 PM, the music video for 'Secret Garden' will be released!
はい、これもなんか良い感じにね、本当になっておりますので、ぜひぜひよろしくお願いいたします。
Yes, this also turned out really well, so please check it out.
ちょっと新曲ってドキドキする。
I'm a bit nervous about the new song.
よし、ということで、じゃあ、６周年締めくくる新オリ曲、やる前に立ち位置確認しよう。
Alright, then, before we perform the new original song to close out the 6th anniversary, let's check our positions.
オッケー！よし、好きなんだよな、この曲。
Okay! Man, I love this song.
よっしゃ、６周年締めて７周年も頑張るぞ！オー！
Alright, let's wrap up the 6th year and do our best for the 7th! Oh!
よっしゃ、みんな立ち位置覚えてる？練習したからいけるやろ。
Alright, everyone remember your positions? We practiced a lot, so we should be fine.
最後の曲だ！
It's the last song!
よし、じゃあ皆さん準備はいいですか？
Alright, everyone ready?
行きますよ、せーの！『Secret Garden』！
Here we go, one, two! 'Secret Garden'!
月夜のセレナーデ
A moonlit serenade
白い薔薇は誰を想う
Who does the white rose think of?
その身を震わせて
With its body trembling
愛を歌うの
It sings of love
零れ落ちた花びらが
The fallen petals
寂しさの跡を隠した
Hid the traces of loneliness
ねぇ早く迎えに来て？
Hey, please come to get me soon?
最後のひとひらが落ちるその前に
Before the very last petal falls
今は　どんな花とも群れないの
Now, I don't flock with any other flowers
あなただけを待ってる
I'm waiting only for you
あなたとならこの体が
If it's with you, even if this body
壊されたってもう構わない
Is broken, I no longer care
棘に触れたら傷つくわ
Touching the thorns will hurt
その覚悟がないなら
If you don't have that resolve
いっそここから消えてよ
Then just disappear from here
重く閉ざした　そう　Secret Garden
Heavily closed, yes, Secret Garden
夜風はリゾルート
The night wind is resolute
白い薔薇は覚醒する
The white rose awakens
背中押されるように
As if being pushed forward
扉開いた
The door opened
ただ独りで枯れてゆくの？
Will I just wither away all alone?
待ってるだけじゃいられない
I can't just keep waiting
衝動の赴くまま
Following my impulses
茨の道を裸足で駆け抜けてく
I'll run through the path of thorns barefoot
凛と　咲き誇る華でありたい
I want to be a flower that blooms with dignity
あなただけを求めて
Seeking only you
逢いにゆくの　どんな遠く
I'm going to see you, no matter how far
離れていても見つけ出せる
I can find you even if we're far apart
暗い世界も怖くない
I'm not afraid of the dark world either
あなたを感じるから
Because I feel you
全て失ったっていい
It's fine even if I lose everything
二度と戻らない　そう　Secret Garden
Never returning, yes, Secret Garden
今は　どんな花とも群れないの
Now, I don't mingle with any other flowers
あなただけを求めて
Seeking only you
霞の向こう　わたしを呼ぶ
Beyond the mist, calling me
鮮やかに燃える強き薔薇
A strong rose burning vividly
凛と　咲き誇る華でありたい
I want to be a flower blooming with dignity
やっとここで出逢えた
Finally, we met here
あなたとならこの身体が
If it's with you, even if this body...
壊されたってもう構わない
is destroyed, I don't care anymore
棘に触れたら傷つくわ
If you touch the thorns, you'll get hurt
その覚悟があるのね
You have that determination, don't you?
手を取り合えば広がる
If we take each other's hands, it expands
誰も知らない　そう
Nobody knows, that's right
Sacred Universe